Guide to the Visiting Faculty Program, Yale Summer and Special Programs, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Visiting Faculty Program, Yale Summer and Special Programs, records
1977-2003
RU 502
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.5
The records consist of administrative and personnel files documenting the activities and operations of the Visiting Faculty Program of Yale Summer and Special Programs.
Yale Summer and Special Programs
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 15-B (YRG 15-B), Records of specific Yale summer and special programs.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative and personnel files documenting the activities and operations of the Visiting Faculty Program of Yale Summer and Special Programs.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Faculty; Yale Summer and Special Programs; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Faculty
- Records of the Visiting Faculty Program, 1977-1978; Accession 1981-A-035
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until January 1, 2053
  - General Visiting Faculty Program, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Originals and chrono correspondence file, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Name lists of fellows, hosts, administrators, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Original correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronological correspondence file, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Visiting Faculty Program, general information, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program evaluations, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Grant proposal drafts, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mellon Foundation, correspondence and memoranda, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Final concerence and luncheon, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mid-winter conference, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Press releases, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Application information, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15 - 16)
  - Financial records, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Records, 1979-1981; Accession 1983-A-045
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
  - 1979-1980
    - Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Applications (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Budget (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chronology (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Conference on writing (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Meetings, receptions (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Press releases (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Reciprocal visits (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Registrations (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1980-1981
    - Benefits (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Chronology (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Duplicates (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Originals (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Fine, Benjamin Fairfield University (Box 4, Folder 70)
- Records of the Visiting Faculty Program, 1979-1982; Accession 1983-A-046
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018.
  - Budget, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Expense Reports, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fellow's Expenses, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Other, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personnel Forms, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Postage Requests/Purchase Requisitions/Stock Requests, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printing Service, Quick Copy, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Request for Services, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Transfers, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Advisory Committee, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application Information, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Conference, 1981 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chrono, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Originals, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Evaluations, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Evaluations, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Publicity, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Reciprocal Visits, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Special Programs - Seminars, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - History/Literature: Versions of the City in American Literature, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Sociobiology, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Literature: Tess of the d'Uberville, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Literature: Critics as Connoisseurs of Chaos, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - History: Historical Thoughts on the Origins of War, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Artificial Intelligence, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Records of the Visiting Faculty Program, 1990-1992; Accession 1997-A-018
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2028
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.
  - Originals, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Financial, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advisory committee, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Application information, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - One day seminars, visiting faculty program (V.F.P.), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - One day seminars, visiting faculty program (VFP), June 4, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - One day seminar, visiting faculty program (VFP), June 5, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - One day seminar, visiting faculty program (VFP), June 6, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - One day seminars, visiting faculty program, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Registration forms, visiting faculty program (VFP), 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Registration forms, visiting faculty program (VFP), 1991 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Registration forms, visiting faculty program (VFP), 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Registration forms, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Records of the Visiting Faculty Program, 1975-2003; Accession 2006-A-151
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
  - General, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Visiting Faculty Program, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Proposal Information, 1979-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Participants, Greene NEH - 82, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1999 Updated forms, letters, etc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1999 Copies of Apps (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1999 Reciprocal Visits (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Symposium, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mellon Foundation VFP, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Princeton, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Stanford, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Check Requests Summer, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Deposits Summer/ELI, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Paid Bills ELI, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Payroll Spring ELI, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Check Requests ELI, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Payroll Fall ELI, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Registration Forms, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Visiting Faculty, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Labels/Lists, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Originals, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Duplicates, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers ELI, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Budget, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Application Info/Materials, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Chrono, 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Evaluations, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - One-Day Rejects, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Receptions/Luncheons/Meetings, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Advisory Committee, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Service Requests, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - ID Information, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Printing/Quick Copy, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Misc. Memos, 2002-2003 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Office Supplies Summer, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Original Documents and Ads, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Fall 2002 Student Payroll (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Spring 2003 Student Payroll (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Application Fee Problems, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Catering Summer, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Paid Bills Summer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Petty Cash Vouchers Summer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Purchasing Card Information, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Purchasing Summer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - RIS Orders Summer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Request for Services Summer, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Travel Requisition Forms, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Summer CASUAL Payroll, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Graduate Student Payroll Summer, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Summer Faculty Memos, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Salary Letters Faculty, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Temporary ID Requests Summer, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Sumer Letters to Instructors, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Summer Over payments, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Payroll Summer, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Statements Summer, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Payroll Summary
    Restricted until January 1, 2074
    - Mu, Ling, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Faculty Salary Problems, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 171)
  - Overpayment Summer, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 172)